# ADITYA KUMAR

 $+91~8434567619 \diamond \text{New Delhi, IN}$ 

aditya208204@gmail.com \leftrightarrow linkedin.com/in/aditya-kumar

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Software Developer with 2.5+ years of experience building data-intensive applications, tackling challenging architectural and scalability problems, and collecting and sorting data in Finance. Well-acquainted with Pipelines, Data structures, Data management, processing systems, and Data Scraping. I strongly desire to move forward, face new challenges, and expand my skill set.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering, Biju Patnaik University of Technology, Odisha 2017 - 2021

#### **SKILLS**

TechnicalJava, SpringBoot, Python, Pandas, Numpy, Django, REST framework, Metplot, Seaborne,SkillsTensorFlow, ML, Flask, Selenium, Data Scraping, JS, HTML, CSS, Doc. using Swagger

Database PostgreSQL, MySQL, AWS S3, AWS EC2, Snowflake

OS Unix/Linux, Windows

Soft Skills Communication Skills, Creativity, Result-oriented

#### EXPERIENCE

## Python Developer

Nexensus(Eagle Peak Intel Pvt. LTD)

April 2022 - Now New Delhi. IN

- Developing a new code to collect data from the source where the data are present as per the requirement.
- Analyzed converted legacy of Financial data and Judgment data compatibility and accuracy.
- Increased the efficiency of the data fetching by approximately 30% using query optimization and indexing.
- Automated the manual data reconciliation process between the different sources, increasing the data accuracy and efficiency by 90%.
- Decreased database load by 26% by refactoring data structures and implementing an update on the event cache.
- Introduced several reusable generic Talent systems that saved up to 50% on development time.
- Developed an ETL system to replace an existing data pipeline built on DTS using Python and PostgreSQL Server.

## **Data Science Intern**

Perfect E-Learning

July 2020 - August 2020 Faridabad, Haryana, IN

- Create intricate data structures to aid in the development of corporate strategies and insights.
- completed a comprehensive review of the metadata and data to ensure that any sensitive information had been found.
- Completed impact analysis on a data warehouse for incoming projects.
- Analysed 10 business processes to collect measurable data.
- Completed 150 hours of training in ETL Pipelines and MySQL.

## **PROJECTS**

Zip Code to Latitude and Longitude API. The Django API provides seamless access to latitude and longitude coordinates by inputting a zip code. It simplifies location-based operations by offering effortless retrieval of geographic data. This API streamline processes requiring geographical coordinates, enhancing efficiency in various applications such as mapping, weather forecasting, and location-based services! (View Repository)

**Breast Cancer Prediction.** This is an analysis of the Breast Cancer (Diagnostic) Data Set, We are going to analyze it and try several machine learning classification models to compare their results. The best model found is based on a neural network and reaches a sensibility of 0.984 with an F1 score of 0.984.(View Repository)

Fruits and Vegetable Recognition System. It is a fruit and vegetable recognition system using CNN and provides recipe suggestions to the user. Users can click vegetable or fruit images using this app. This CNN model predicts the provided image and gives the available recipe suggestions as well as the procedures. (View Repository)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• June 2024, AWS Solution Architect	EdYoda
• September 2023, Data Visualisation: Empowering Business with Effective Insights	Forage
• September 2021, Cognizant USA Ready, Set, Agile! Virtual Experience Program	Forage
• September 2020, Certified Python Data-Structures Machine Learning	Perfect E-Learning
• July 2020, Certified Python for Data Science	IBM
• August 2018, Certified MTA: Introduction to Programming Language in Java	MTA

## **LANGUAGES**

- Hindi, Native Speaker
- English